Martha Hewitt Papers
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Martha Hewitt Papers.
undated, 1911-1969.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Hewitt, Martha.
1.25 linear feet.
Martha Hewitt was the wife of Dr. Harold Hewitt. Dr. Hewitt was a professor of chemistry and Dean of the School of Pharmacy at the University of Connecticut from 1947 until his retirement in February 1972. The collection contains a small amount of correspondence from Martha Hewitt to her family while traveling in Europe, documentation for her application to the DAR and other random personal papers. The majority of the photographs are of Mrs. Hewitt's family, although there are some of Dr. Hewitt.
MSS20080042
Biography
Harold G. Hewitt received his degrees from the University of Wisconsin (B.S. 1923, M.S. 1925, Ph.D. 1926). In 1926, he married Martha Alexander and the couple moved to Buffalo, NY, where Harold had received an appointment to the faculty at the University of Buffalo as head of the Division of Chemistry in the School of Pharmacy. In 1947, Harold G. Hewitt was selected by President Albert N. Jorgensen to fill the office of Dean of the School of Pharmacy (then located in New Haven) at the University of Connecticut. Dr. Hewitt served as Dean until 1969 and retired from the University in 1972. While at the University of Connecticut, the Hewitts were close friends of Geraldine and Charles Waring. The Warings had arrived in Connecticut the year before and Charles and Harold shared a similar background in Chemistry.
Harold Hewitt died in the Spring of 1980. Mrs. Hewitt died sometime in the 1980s. Geraldine Waring was the executrix for Martha Hewitt's estate.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains a small amount of correspondence from Martha Hewitt to her family while traveling in Europe, documentation for her application to the DAR and other random personal papers. The collection also includes personal, family and professional activity (of Harold Hewitt) photographs.
Arrangement
Series I: Personal Papers ( undated, 1923-1930 )
Series II: Photographs ( undated, 1911-1969 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Hewitt, Martha.; Hewitt, Harold.
Places:
Storrs, Conn.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.; School Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The materials in the collection were found amongst those of Geraldine Waring at the time when Mrs. Waring's estate donated the materials in the Charles E. Waring Papers.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by the estate of Geraldine Waring in 2008.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Personal Papers, undated, 1923-1930
  - Astrological readings, 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Calling/At Home cards, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution materials, 1924, 1926 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Marriage announcement, 1926 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Merrill genealogy, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Monogram, undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation, 1923 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - School records, 1927 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Trip to Japan, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
- Series II: Photographs, undated, 1911-1969
  - Martha Alexander Hewitt, undated, 1911, 1917 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Martha Alexander Hewitt, undated (Box 2:, Folder 14-15)
  - Martha and Harold Hewitt wedding, [1926] (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - Martha and Harold Hewitt, undated, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - Harold Hewitt, undated, 1969 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - Martha and Harold Hewitt (Groups), undated, 1969 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Dr. B. E. Hewitt, 1919 October (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - Alexander Family, undated (Box 2:, Folder 21)